SOURAV DUTTA

https://sourav-oss.github.io
Medinipur, West Bengal, 721516
sodutta1234@gmail.com | 7585906864



About Me-

I am a web application developer with hands-on skills and several years of experiences in a wide range of software, tools and programming languages. For the last few years, I have been working nearly with backend technologies like Node.js and Express.js. I have learnt to determine operational feasibility by evaluating analysis, problem definition, requirements, solution development, and to propose solutions. Programming is my passion.

Objective -

Secure a responsible career opportunity to fully utilize my trainings and skills, while making a significant contribution to the success of the organization.

I am willing to relocate anywhere. I am fond of learning new tools and technologies.

Work Experience -

A) Software Engineer

June 2022 - Present

Indus Net Technologies Pvt Ltd, Kolkata, India

> Software Engineer (Front-end Development)

June 2022

B) Senior Front-end Developer (Team Leader)

April 2019 – May 2022

Webhibe Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Kolkata, India

- > Team Leader (Front-end Development)
 December 2021
- > Senior Front-end Developer March 2020
- > Web Designer
 April 2019

Skills & Technologies -

My expertises are HTML, CSS, Bootstrap & CSS libraries, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, React-Redux, Next.js, Strapi, REST APIs, PHP, Photoshop, Figma, Git version control, Progressive Web Application and Responsive Website Design.

Personal Skills -

- Base Strong understanding and experience on programming, web concepts and frontend technologies. Design, code, test, review, build and release.
- Open Always up for new ideas and able to take and give feedback in a positive way.
- Driven Sets high goals, doesn't give up, and motivated to ensure that their job gets done on time and meets/exceeds expectations.

- Curious Aware of new technologies and uses them to make new improvements in the Engineering ecosystem.
- Smart Innovative and thinks out of the box, in difficult situations finds a way to succeed.
- Responsible Takes ownership of tasks given and has a strong work ethic.

Education -

Bachelor's Degree - Computer Application

Jul 2016 - Aug 2019

Vinayaka Mission Sikkim University, Kolkata, India

Higher Secondary (10+2) - Science

Jun 2014 - May 2016

West Bengal Council of Higher Secondary Education (WBCHSE)

Certificate in Computer Application

October 2014

Sahaj Tathya Mitra Kendra (Govt. of WB) - SA/WB/CCA/424/Oct14

Contact Details -

Website: https://sourav-oss.github.io/

Email: sodutta1234@gmail.com

Call: 7585906864

Location: Malida, Pirakata, Paschim Medinipur, West Bengal, 721516, India

[✓] I hereby declare that all statements made in this resume are true, complete and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.